

#### **Profile**

# Oluwatosin Oloruntoba WEB DEVELOPER

Backend engineer with 7 years' experience in building quality solutions for individuals, businesses and government using HTML5, CSS, jQuery, PHP, SQL with a commitment to writing highly performing and easily maintainable codes.

### **Projects**

#### National Identity Management System (NIMC) Integration

MAY 2021 - OCTOBER 2021

Development of an API to request for an individual's data from the national databank using the National Identification Number (NIN).

Technologies used in this project are:

PHP and SQL

#### Federal Capital Territory Public Transport Management System (FCT PTMS)

JUNE 2020- TILL DATE

Development and maintenance of a web portal for the registration and licensing and monitoring of public transport within the country's capital. It involves retrieval of prospective riders' record from the national databank, validation of rider's vehicle and driving licensing and mapping of each rider to his/her vehicle to aid security checks.

Technologies used in this project are:

HTML5, CSS3, jQuery, AJAX, PHP, SQL

#### **Telospace**

SEPTEMBER 2019- TILL DATE

Developed the API for the mobile application (an Android bill payments application) which integrated to third-party endpoints for vending and funding the wallet system. Also, developed the admin-end for reporting. I also provide maintenance and update when needed

Technologies used in this project are:

- PHP for developing the API
- HTML5, CSS3, jQuery, AJAX, PHP, SQL for the admin reporting UI
- MySQL for database management

#### **Astute Portal**

JUNE 2019 - TILL DATE

Developed a management system and e-payment solution for a school. It is used to register new and existing students, staff and parents. It also manages the cash flow of the accounting department by recording expenditures by bank or cash and cash inflow. In addition, it integrates to a payment platform to allow online payment of fees and other dues with a proper reporting system.

#### **Contact Details**

ayodejioluwatosin4@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/tos indeji-toba

#### Skills

Attention to Detail

Complex Problem Solving

PHP

HTML5 & CSS3

jQuery

SQL

AJAX

Microsoft Power BI

#### Languages

English

#### Hobbies

Meeting people, listening to music/talk shows

Technologies used in this project are:

- HTML5, CSS3, jQuery, AJAX, PHP, SQL
- MySQL for database management

#### **Vuvaa Agent**

APRIL 2018 - TILL DATE

Development of a RESTful API service for a mobile banking platform. It communicates with the mobile applications and Point of Sale (POS) terminals for transactions. I also handled the merchant settlement platform.

Technologies used in this project are:

- PHP for developing the API
- HTML5, CSS3, jQuery, AJAX, PHP, SQL for the admin reporting UI
- MySQL for database management

#### Nigerian Inter-Bank Settlement System (NIBSS) Integration

JULY 2017 - AUGUST 2017

Integrated the company's wallet system to NIBSS platform to allow real-time payment into the wallet from any bank branch or platform

Technologies used in this project are:

PHP, SQL, XML

#### **Abuja Inspector**

OCTOBER 2017 - TILL DATE

Development and maintenance of a RESTful API service to provide vehicle inspection officers information about vehicles on-the-go when on road patrol for proper identification of defaulting officers. It allows offers modules to book offenders, generate and make payment for offences, make payment for pins needed to register or renewal vehicle licenses.

Technologies used in this project are:

• PHP and SQL for developing the API

#### **Lagos State Computerized Vehicle Inspection Service (LACVIS)**

JULY 2017 - TILL DATE

Developed a RESTful API for the integration of the mobile application to the backend services for payment and pin generation required to perform vehicle inspection in the state. In charge of the maintenance and updates on request of the admin portal for report generation, settlement generation and users management.

Technologies used in this project are:

- PHP for developing the API
- HTML5, CSS3, jQuery, AJAX, PHP, SQL for the admin reporting UI
- · MySQL for database management

# **Employment History**

#### Senior Web Developer, Access Solutions Limited, Abuja

OCTOBER 2017 — TILL DATE

As a web developer, I ensure the development of optimized backend codes that will integrate to third party solutions to deliver data to the UI on-demand for the overall development of quality solutions.

Some of my achievements include:

- Integration to Nigerian Inter-Bank Settlement System (NIBSS) eBillspay Platform
- Integration to Interswitch PayDirect payment system
- Integration to Remita platform
- Integration to eTranzact bill payment platform
- Integration to National Identity Management System (NIMC) platform
- Development of API for agency banking solution
- Development of API for church devotional
- Member of development and maintenance team for different state electronic
  Vehicle inspection platforms
- Part of development team for different recruitment portals for government agencies

#### **Web Developer Intern, Access Solutions Limited, Abuja**

APRIL 2017 — SEPTEMBER 2017

Some of my achievements include:

 Development of a documentation for the company's software framework to aid new staff

#### Student Intern, Netpoint Communications, Ibadan, Oyo State

JUNE 2014 - DECEMBER 2014

Some of my achievements include:

- Maintenance of existing solution for an eatery
- Development of an inventory solution for an X-ray centre
- Part of the team for the development of a car recovery solution

#### **Educational Institution**

#### MSc Information Technology, National Open University of Nigeria

JUNE 2019 — JANUARY 2022

# **B.**Tech Computer Science, Federal University of Technology, Akure, Nigeria

OCTOBER 2010 - SEPTEMBER 2015

# **Professional Qualification**

#### **Project Management Professional, British Project Management Academy**

OCTOBER 2017

#### Courses

#### **AWS She Builds CloudUp - Cloud Practitioner Program, AWS**

FEBRUARY 2022 - MARCH 2022

#### Data Analysis with Power BI, Barian Systems, Abuja

AUGUST 2021

# Awards and Achievements

Most Outstanding Staff of the Year, Access Solutions Limited, Abuja

#### References

#### References available upon request